humankinetics.com 2018-09-21

# What is the Human Kinetics Privacy Policy?

**What is the Human Kinetics Privacy Policy?**

European customers please click [here](https://uk.humankinetics.com/pages/privacy-policy "Europe’s privacy policy") to view our European Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting HumanKinetics.com. This Privacy Policy will tell you:

  * What information we collect
  * How we may use your information
  * How you can limit our sharing of information

This site is governed by the Privacy Policy of Human Kinetics, Inc. We reserve the right to make changes to our site, policies, and this Privacy Policy at any time, so please check back periodically. Questions regarding this Policy should be directed to [webmaster@hkusa.com](mailto:webmaster@hkusa.com) or may also be sent in writing to:

Human Kinetics, Inc.

Attn: Website Manager

1607 N. Market Street

PO Box 5076

Champaign, IL 61825-5076

**What We Collect**

Human Kinetics Inc., and its subsidiaries (collectively HK hereafter), recognize the importance of protecting the information gathered from users in the operation of this website and takes reasonable steps to maintain the security, integrity and privacy of any information collected. Although HK employs reasonable measures in connection with the collection, storage, and disclosure of information through the website, you should be aware that the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to/from HK through this website or by e-mail cannot be guaranteed. Therefore, HK is not responsible for the security of information transmitted via the Internet. By submitting your information to HK you consent to the practices described herein.

HK collects information about individuals as provided on a voluntary basis such as during the ordering process, website registration, online courses, certification tests, conference attendance, catalog requests, surveys, or e-mail subscription requests.

Users should be aware that when they voluntarily disclose Personally Identifiable Information (e.g., user name, e-mail address, phone number) on bulletin boards, blogs or in chat areas of the HK site, or sites of any related companies or subsidiaries, that information, along with any substantive information disclosed in the user’s communication, can be collected and used by third parties who are not affiliated with HK. Although HK takes every precaution possible to protect your information, by choosing to post personal information in areas that are viewable to all site visitors, such as forums and blogs, you are doing so at your own risk. Posting personal information may result in unsolicited messages from other posters or third parties. Such activities are not facilitated by HK and are beyond our control.

**Cookies**

Users should be aware that non-personal information and data may be automatically collected through the standard operation of HK’s internet servers or through the use of "cookies." "Cookies" are small text files a web site can use to recognize repeat users, facilitate the user’s ongoing access to and use of the site, and allow a site to track usage behavior and compile aggregate data that will allow content improvements and targeted advertising. Cookies are not programs that come onto a user’s system and damage files. Generally, cookies work by assigning a unique number to the user that has no meaning outside the assigning site. If a user does not want information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows the user to deny or accept the cookie feature; however, users should note that cookies may be necessary to provide the user with certain features available on HumanKinetics.com.

**How We Use Your Information**

HK reserves the right to contact a user regarding product orders, support issues and other matters relevant to the underlying service and/or the information collected.

Contact information such as name, address, and e-mail, may be shared with subsidiaries of HK, and may be used by such subsidiaries to send promotional and/or marketing information about other products, services and offerings from HK and/or its subsidiaries. Instructions on how to unsubscribe are included in every promotional e-mail.

**Use of email addresses.** HK does not rent, sell, exchange, or share e-mail addresses with third parties (i.e., any entity besides Human Kinetics, Inc. and its subsidiaries) except when individuals specifically consent to allow us to do so by checking a permission box via our website or other official HK communications.

Information or files e-mailed to software technical support or sent through the technical support request system integrated into the HK site will not be used for internal marketing and sales purposes, or be sold or otherwise transferred to unaffiliated third parties.

**Use of postal addresses.** Postal address information will not be shared with third parties without your permission, or where expressly forbidden by local privacy acts or legislation. When HK shares your postal address information with a third party, your personal information will become permanently subject to the information use and sharing practices of the third party, and the third party will not be restricted by this Privacy Policy with respect to its use and further sharing of your personal information. For more details on the sharing of postal addresses in each specific region, please see Regional Privacy below.

HK reserves the right to perform statistical analyses of user behavior and characteristics in order to measure interest in and use of the various areas of the site; this analysis will sometimes be used to inform advertisers of site performance. HK will provide only anonymous, aggregated data from these analyses to third parties.

We may release account information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to enforce or apply our Terms and Conditions; to protect the rights, property, and safety of HK’s e-commerce site, our users, or others; or to conform to the requirements of law or comply with governmental orders, court orders, or legal process served on us. If customers do not pay us for products ordered, we may submit their account information to a third-party collection agency.

**Opt Out Details**

Upon request, HK will allow any user to "opt out" of further promotional contacts at any time. Additionally upon request, HK will use reasonable efforts to allow users to update/correct personal information previously submitted which the user states is erroneous to the extent such activities will not compromise privacy or security interests. Also, upon a user’s request, HK will use commercially reasonable efforts to functionally delete the user and his or her personal information from its database; however, it may be impossible to delete a user’s entry without some residual information because of backups and records of deletions. Please contact us with any opt out requests.

**Regional Privacy**

When information is collected, the user will have the opportunity to indicate whether he or she would like to "opt in" to receiving promotional and/or marketing information about other products, services, and offerings from HK and/or any third parties. More region-specific information is provided in this section.

**Australian Customers**

Human Kinetics Australia Pty Ltd (HKA) respects the privacy of individuals and maintains, uses, and discloses personal information and the user’s rights of access and correction in accordance with the National Privacy Principles contained in the Privacy Act 1988. If you have any questions concerning HK Australia’s Privacy Policy, please contact us at [info@hkaustralia.com](mailto:info@hkaustralia.com) or PO Box 80, Torrens Park SA 5062.

**Canadian Customers**

Human Kinetics Canada respects the privacy of individuals and maintains, uses, and discloses personal information and the user’s rights of access and correction in accordance with the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act. If you have any questions concerning HK Canada’s Privacy Policy, please contact us at [info@hkcanada.com](mailto:info@hkcanada.com) or write to us at:

475 Devonshire Road, Unit 100,

Windsor, Ontario, Canada

N8Y 2L5

**European Customers**

Any personal information provided to or gathered by HK from users within Europe is controlled by Human Kinetics Europe Ltd, a company registered in England and Wales (Company No. 2282338), with a registered office at 107 Bradford Road, Stanningley, Leeds LS28 6AT. We are registered with the Information Commissioner in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, Data Protection Registration no. Z6111762.

If you wish to update your interests or communication preferences please contact us at the above address, call +44 (0) 113 255 5665 or email [hk@hkeurope.com](mailto:hk@hkeurope.com).

**United States Customers**

Human Kinetics, Inc. will not sell, trade, share, or rent your Personally Identifiable Information to others without your consent. When sharing your information for promotional purposes, HK attempts to select only reputable companies that offer high quality products and services. When you provide HK your account and order information, you will have the opportunity to indicate whether you would like to give HK permission to share your Personally Identifiable Information with third parties so they may send you promotional and/or marketing information about their products, services, and offerings. When you give HK permission and HK shares your personal information with a third party, your personal information will become permanently subject to the information use and sharing practices of the third party, and the third party will not be restricted by this Privacy Policy with respect to its use and further sharing of your personal information.

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of HK who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us.

Users may opt out of receiving third-party mailings at any time by contacting us.

**Links To and From Other Websites**

Users should be aware that links may be provided from HumanKinetics.com to other websites. Each website will vary in terms of its privacy and data protection policies. HK does not accept responsibility for the privacy policies of, and usage of, personal information collected by others including those of any partner or affiliate.

**Warning about Fraudulent Emails**

We will never request your password, user name, credit card information or other personal information through e-mail. This practice, frequently called "phishing", is an illegal practice designed to steal your personal information. If you receive an e-mail that looks like it is from us asking you for your personal information, please do not respond and notify us immediately.

**Children’s Privacy**

Users must be at least 18 years of age in order to have permission to use this site. We are committed to protecting children’s privacy on the Internet. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18. If a child has provided our website with personally identifiable information, we ask that a parent or guardian contact us and we will delete the information about the child from our files.

**Your Consent**

By using our website, you consent to our use of information that is collected or submitted as described in this online Privacy Policy. We may change or add to this Privacy Policy so we encourage you to review it periodically.

**Contacting Human Kinetics, Inc. About Privacy Questions or Concerns**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, or if at any point you wish to access your personal information to make changes, review the accuracy of your information, or supplement or modify your information, you may use the contact us by e-mail at [info@hkusa.com](mailto:info@hkusa.com) or by sending a written request to:

Human Kinetics Inc.

Attn: Website Manager

1607 N. Market Street

PO Box 5076

Champaign, IL 61825-5076

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

The foregoing policies are effective as of April 22, 2014. We may change, modify, add, or remove portions of this Policy at any time, and any changes will become effective immediately upon posting. This statement and the policies outlined herein are not intended to, and do not create, any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any party.
